

Maximilien Mellen Software Engineer

### About me

I am a full-stack software engineer focused on building simple and elegant solutions to complex problems. I approach challenges holistically to build cohesive and engaging user experiences. I strive to always challenge myself as well as my coworkers to help create an environment that encourages learning and growth, both personally and as a team.

### Languages

- \* English
  Native proficiency
- \* French
  Native proficiency
- **→ German** *Limited working proficiency*
- Spanish
  Limited working proficiency

#### Education

DUT in Computer Science at Université Savoie Mont-Blanc

## **Experience**

02.2019 - Today

### Software Engineer

Arweave

- Develop web applications interacting with the Arweave blockchain in TypeScript, React and Vue.js
- \* Extend Arweave node software written in Erlang to ease integration with current web technologies
- Leverage modern cloud platforms and third-party services to deploy "serverless" applications

12.2017 - 01.2019

# Software Engineer

- Implement a high-performance, concurrent, intermodal journey search engine in Elixir/OTP
- Help web client team integrate new payment system and flow using React and Redux
- Communicate product concerns across back-end and client teams to align entire development team
- Coach web team to adopt functional programming and strong typing with TypeScript

04.2016 - 11.2017

## Lead Developer

Webmecanik

- Implement marketing automation account management platform in Laravel and Vue.js
- Contribute to open-source marketing automation project Mautic written in Symfony
- Help development team learn new technologies and improve testing and code review practices
- Play an integral role in the relationship between the company and the Mautic open-source project